Casey Golightly Chamberlain

Full Stack Web Developer · Software Engineer

1505 Commons Ford Pl, Apex, NC, 27539

(385)-201-5044 | caseygchamberlain@gmail.com | Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

"One day or day one. You decide."

Summary

Recent full stack web developer graduate with previous analyst experience. Professionally educated at the University of Utah. Graduated from the University's Coding Bootcamp in the spring of 2022. Strengths in teamwork, meeting deadlines, creativity, and self reliance. Known to be a hyper focused and determined individual passionate about developing full stack web applications.

My technical experience as an international shipping analyst for one of "America's Best Midsize Employers" (Forbes), has taught me the importance of the corporate environment and communication. My past experience makes me a strong addition as a developer with a mindset geared towards the small details and the user.

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- MySQL
- Express.js

- React.js
- Node.js
- Heroku
- Bootstrap
- jQuery

- Handlebars.js
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Git

Work Experience

Lightly LLCFounder, CEO, & Software Engineer

Raleigh, NC Jan. 2023 - Present

- Freelance web developer.
- Design and code modern and professional front-end web applications for clients' needs.
- Successfully communicate and consult with clients about projects' scope, vision, and functionality.
- Adhere to SCRUM and AGILE methodologies.

doTERRA

Pleasant Grove, UT

Australia/New Zealand Shipping Analyst

Jun. 2019 - Dec. 2022

- Communicate with the Operations department in the head office of Australia to ensure inventory and shipping performance regarding warehouse and carrier services.
- Subject matter expert regarding all domestic and international shipments between the United States of America, Australia, and New Zealand.
- 10+ Top Adherence awards.
- 5 MVP awards.

Brian Head Resort

Brian Head, UT

Nov. 2019 - Apr. 2020

Lead Lift Operator

- Team leader of 3-4 lift operators.
- Closely work with mechanics to ensure safe ski lift operations.
- Closely work with ski patrol to ensure mountain and customer safety.

Honors & Awards

- 2022 Coding Bootcamp Full Stack Developer, Credly
- 2018 Varsity Track & Field, American Fork High School
- 2017 Varsity Cross Country, American Fork High School
- 2016 Varsity Cross Country, American Fork High School
- 2016 **Eagle Scout**, Boy Scouts of America

Education

University of Utah

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Git, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and React.js.

American Fork High School

Diploma, Honors

- Team captain of nationally ranked cross country team.
- French club.